XuetangX MOOC OSSG: Ray
学堂在线MOOC开源字幕组：含光
For example, we can make improvements according to such a demostration
比如说，我们可以按照这样的一个图示来进行改进
Specifically
具体来说
We always divide the entire sequence into two parts on the left and right each time
我们总是把整个这个序列每次都划分为左侧和右侧两部分
Here I might as well draw them vertically
这里我不妨把它们垂直地画上
It doesn’t matter, for example, the left side and the right side
这个无所谓，比如说左侧和右侧
what's next
接下来呢
We solve two subproblems recursively
我们递归地求解两个子问题
Find the largest element and the second largest element on the left, respectively
分别求出左侧的最大元素和次大元素
And the largest and second largest elements on the right
以及右侧的最大元素和次大元素
what's next
接下来呢
The global largest element must come from the larger one between
全局的最大元必然来自于左侧的最大元和右侧的最大元之间的更大者
For this we need to spend a comparison
为此我们需要花费一次比较
Then of course there are two situations
那么当然有两种情况
So here is a symmetrical situation
所以这里呢画出对称的情况
It may indeed be the biggest one on the left wins
可能确实是左侧这个最大者胜出
Or maybe the biggest one on the right wins
也可能是右侧这个最大者胜出
Without loss of generality, let’s consider the one on the left.
不失一般性，我们先考虑左侧的这个
the right side is symmetrical.
右侧完全对称的
If after a comparison, we confirm that the left side wins
如果经过一次比较以后我们确认左侧的胜出
Then we can proceed to the conclusion
那么我们又可以进而得出结论
The global second largest element must come from the second largest element
全局次大元素必然是来自于左侧的次大元，
on the left, and just now, if it was defeated, the largest element on the right
和这个刚才，如果说是败下来的，右侧的最大元
Similarly, we can confirm the winner among them through a comparison
同样，我们通过一次比较就可以确认他们中间的胜者
Attention, here, the second largest sub-problem that we just failed does not need to participate in the comparison.
大家注意，在这里， 我们刚才失败的那个子问题中的次大者无需参与比较
Let's take a look
我们来看一下
Such ideas can be organized into such a piece of code
这样的思路可以整理为这样一段代码
Of course there are also degraded situations here
当然这里也有退化的情况
We put the realization and explanation of such a degraded situation
我们把这样的退化情况的实现和解释
This task
这个任务
Leave it to the students to finish after class
留给同学们在课后完成
Generally speaking
一般而言
We all take the midpoint of lo and hi
我们都是取lo和hi的中点
And
并且
Recursively solve
递归地求解出刚刚我们所说的
the x1L, x2L and x1R, x2R we just mentioned
x1L, x2L 以及 x1R, x2R
Next, we compare the largest of the two subintervals once
接下来我们对两个子区间的最大者进行1次比较
You can determine the winner
就可以确定其中的胜者
Is the biggest of the whole world
也就是全局的最大者
Or him (x1L), or him (x1R)
或者是他(x1L)，或者是他(x1R)
Well, just now we said
那么，刚才我们说了
The picture on the left corresponds to the case of if
左边这个图，对应的是if这个情况
The picture on the right corresponds to the situation of else
右边这个图，对应的是else这个情况
Furthermore, how to determine the global second largest element x2?
进而，全局的次大元素x2怎么来确定呢
We can see that
我们可以看到
Whether it is if or else
无论是 if 还是 else
He is symmetrical
他都是对称的
We just need to compare again
我们只需要再进行一次比较
This comparison actually corresponds to this
这次比较其实对应的就是这个
Let's review again
我们再回顾一下
Just now this is a comparison
刚才这是比较
Actually, corresponds to this
其实对应的是，它
Or that
或者是说，它
The latter two comparisons
后面这两次比较
Correspondingly, this
对应的是，它
Or that
或者是，它
We can see that
我们可以看到
Anyway
无论如何
In every recursive instance
在每一个递归实例中
Even in the worst case
即便在最坏的情况
We only need to do it once at most
我们至多只需要进行一次
And compare twice
和两次比较
This is why
这也是为什么
This can be written in a recursive equation
可以用递推方程的方式写出来
T(n) should be a subproblem equal to twice the scale of T(n/2)
T(n) 应该是等于两倍的 T(n/2) 规模的子问题
Which is T(n/2)
也就是 T(n/2)
Plus
再加上
just now
刚才的
Two comparisons
两次比较
Recursive
这样一个递推式
Use the same method as before
用前面类似的方法
We can solve
我们可以去求解
Get 5n/3-2
得到 5n/3 - 2
Of course, if you don’t know the specific solution
当然，如果你不知道具体的求解方法的话
You might as well go verify
你不妨去验证一下
We say that this result is very easy to verify
我们说，这种结果是非常好验证的
According to such a formula
按照这样的一个公式
It can be concluded that T(n/2) is
可以得出来 T(n/2) 是多少
Then substitute in
然后代进去
It is not difficult to verify such a result
不难验证这样一个结果
What we need to point out here is
我们这里需要指出的是
Indeed we can see
确实我们可以看到
If the previous method
如果此前的方法
The number of comparisons required in the worst case
在最坏情况下所需要的比较次数
In terms of the constant coefficient of n
就 n 的常系数而言
If it is 2
如果是 2 的话
now
现在
it's here
在这里
Down to 5/3
降为了 5/3
We can see that
我们可以看到
He has a definite drop
他有一个确定的下降
This decline, let me emphasize again
这种下降 再强调一下
even in the worst case
是即便在最坏情况下
Can also be guaranteed
也能够保证的
Of course, in the best case
当然，在最好情况下
How good would it be
能够多少
We also put this question
我们也把这个问题
Leave it to everyone to think after class
留给大家在课后思考
So to summarize
所以概括一下
The main content of our section is
我们这一节的主要内容是
Teach you iterative and recursive algorithms
教给了大家迭代和递归的算法
Strategies that include two important algorithms
包括两种重要的算法的策略
Reduce and conquer and divide and conquer
减而治之和分而治之
more importantly
更重要的是
Introduction and examples of combining these two strategies
结合这两种策略的介绍和实例
We give
我们给出了
Two typical common analysis methods of recursive algorithms
递归算法的两种典型的常用的分析方法
Recursive tracking and recursive
也就是递归跟踪和递推式
Later
在后边
We will see
我们将会看到
More and more complicated
更多更复杂的
Examples in this regard
这方面的例子